Guide to the Stanford University, Center for Russian, East European and Eurasian Studies, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Center for Russian, East European and Eurasian Studies, records
1972-2002
SC0921
CREEES.
Stanford University. Center for Russian, East European & Eurasian Studies.
1.75 Linear feet
Records include grant proposals, budgets, and reports, 1984-2000; a few files on courses, 1973-93; fund raising files; files on visiting scholars and faculty, 1985-2000; and assorted informational and administrative files, 1972-2002, including reports from Slavianskii Dom, a student theme house on campus, 1987-89.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Center for Russian, East European & Eurasian Studies (CREEES) at Stanford was established in 1969. Their mission is the promotion and support of interdisciplinary study of the nations and peoples of the former Soviet Union, Central and Eastern Europe, and Central Asia.
Description of the Collection
Records include grant proposals, budgets, and reports, 1984-2000; a few files on courses, 1973-93; fund raising files; files on visiting scholars and faculty, 1985-2000; and assorted informational and administrative files, 1972-2002, including reports from Slavianskii Dom, a student theme house on campus, 1987-89.
Access Terms
Stanford University -- General subdivision--Administration.;; Stanford University. Center for Russian, East European & Eurasian Studies.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2008-321
  - Grant Proposal, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Title VI Renewal application, 1985 November (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Title VI Renewal application, 1986 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Title VI Renewal, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Title VI, continuation, partial report, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DOE Budget Analyses/Allocations, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Title VI Application, 1988 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Title VI Renewal application, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Title VI Application, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Title VI Renewal application, 1991 November (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Title VI Application, 1992 November (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Grant application, 1993 October (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Title VI Application, 1993 November (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Proposal to U.S. Dept. of Education, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Title VI continuation application, 1994 November (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Title VI Readers' evaluations, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Title VI Budget revision, 1994 April (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Title VI Notification, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Title VI notice of award, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Title VI award notification, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Title VI award notification, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Title VI award notification, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Title VI Report, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Title VI Report, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Title VI Report, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Title VI Report, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Title VI Revised budget, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Title VI Budget drafts, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Title VI Budget, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Title VI Budget revision, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Title VI Budget revision, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Abstract appendices, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Title VI Reviewers comments, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Title VI Foreign Language Area Program Proposal-originals, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CREEES, information on, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brochures and miscellaneous publications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - FLAS fellowships, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hotline project, info, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Slavic Civilization course-general, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Courses, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Core Course, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Courses, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ivo Andric book, correspondence and preface, 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Slavianskii Dom-theme house reports, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - AAASS-Vucinich Prize, 1982-2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Kosciuszko Foundation, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Alexander Dallin Fund, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Konstanty Stys (Polish) Fund, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New fund numbers, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CREEES miscellaneous income, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - CREEES operating budget, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report, The 1972 Ford Foundation Transitional Grant for International Studies, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fund raising-Alex Dallin, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Kendall Fund, report and request, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Arutiunov/Joukoskaia: CREEES lecturer, 1993 Spring-1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Amsterdamski, Stefan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Brown, Archie, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Burlatsky, Fyodor, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Brandes, Detlef, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Banac, Ivo, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Babinski, Gregorz, Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bolkhovitinov, Nikolai, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Confino, Michael, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Djukanovic, Bojka, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Draganova, Ludmila, Ukranian, 1993 Autumn (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Drobizheva, Ledkadia, 1989 November (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Emmert, Thomas, visiting professor, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Eidelman, Natan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Fondahl, Gail, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Foster-Simons, Frances, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Hankiss, Elemer, political science, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Haslam, Jonathan, 1986-1994 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Shamberg, Vladimir, Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Hrabal, Bohumil, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kamenskii, Alexandr, 1991-2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kabochkina, Tamara, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sakhavor, Andrei and Ludmila Kolodnikova, Inst. Of History, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Startsev, Vitali, Herzen Institute, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Tartakovskii, Andrei, Inst. Of History, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gibianskii, Leonid, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Barnes, Irina; Kollmann, Jack E., Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Krylova, Tatiana, Friends of Raisa Visiting Scholar, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Zaslavsky, Victor, Visiting faculty, 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Panova, Galina, Raisa Gorbachev Partnership in Learning, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Arutiunov, Sergei, CREEES visiting lecturer, 1994 Spring (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Restricted files (Box 5)